<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Blog on Digital Accessibility</title><description>Practical advice on digital accessibility for frontend developers, QA testers and designers. Here you'll learn about methods of creating accessible and user-friendly interfaces, standards, assistive technologies and laws.</description><language></language><link>https://tatiana-fokina-blog.ru/</link><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tatiana-fokina-blog.ru/en/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Role attribute with multiple values</title><description>In what cases may be necessary to set multiple values for a role attribute, and how browsers and screen readers deal with this.</description><link>https://tatiana-fokina-blog.ru/en/articles/aria-attribute-role-with-multiple-values/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://tatiana-fokina-blog.ru/en/articles/aria-attribute-role-with-multiple-values/</guid></item><item><title>How to avoid harming users with epilepsy and vestibular impairment</title><description>What if the user gets motion sickness because of a website? What if he or she has an epileptic seizure? Let&#39;s look at what interfaces for users with epilepsy and vestibular impairment should look like.</description><link>https://tatiana-fokina-blog.ru/en/articles/how-to-protect-users-with-epilepsy-and-vd/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://tatiana-fokina-blog.ru/en/articles/how-to-protect-users-with-epilepsy-and-vd/</guid></item><item><title>Everything you need to know about ARIA Live Regions</title><description>If you have a dynamically changing part of a page and you&#39;re thinking about making it accessible, there may be a legitimate question about how to do it. In the past, assistive technologies (including screen readers) didn&#39;t know how to handle them properly. Now the problem of accessibility of dynamically changing page content can be solved with ARIA.</description><link>https://tatiana-fokina-blog.ru/en/articles/aria-live-regions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://tatiana-fokina-blog.ru/en/articles/aria-live-regions/</guid></item><item><title>CSS media feature to improve accessibility</title><description>What custom settings come and how to take them into account in web interfaces. You will learn about media features that track animation settings, contrast, transparency, inversion, colour scheme and forced colour mode.</description><link>https://tatiana-fokina-blog.ru/en/articles/css-media-features-for-a11y/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://tatiana-fokina-blog.ru/en/articles/css-media-features-for-a11y/</guid></item><item><title>Understanding skip link</title><description>How to skip large navigation with skip link, who needs it and what are the approaches to implementing skip content pattern.</description><link>https://tatiana-fokina-blog.ru/en/articles/understanding-a-skip-link/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://tatiana-fokina-blog.ru/en/articles/understanding-a-skip-link/</guid></item></channel></rss>